Finding Aid for the Arthur William Ingersoll Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Arthur William Ingersoll Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0223
3.78 linear_feet
OBITUARY- Arthur W. Ingersoll (Alumnus Magazine, Vol. 54, No. 4, Mar.-Apr. 1969, p. 46)
ARTHUR W. INGERSOLL, Professor Emeritus of Organic Chemistry, died March 11 after a short illness. Professor Ingersoll, a member of the active faculty from 1922 until 1963, served as secretary of the graduate faculty in 1956. He was the author of a laboratory textbook in organic chemistry. A native of Otoe County, Nebraska, he earned B.S. and M.S. degrees at the University of Nebraska and a Ph.D. from the University of Illinois. He was a member of Phi Beta Kappa, Omicron Delta Kappa, and Sigma Xi, honorary scientific society. Survivors include Mrs. Ingersoll, 2305 Elliston Place, Nashville; a son, Arthur William Ingersoll, Jr., Minneapolis, Minnesota; a nephew, James H. Cordner, Murreysville, Pennsylvania, Who grew up in the Ingersoll home; four grandchildren and two sisters.
B.S. - Nebraska - 1917
M.S. - Nebraska - 1918
Ph.D. - Illinois - 1922 (Faculty Register)
Assistant Professor of Organic Chemistry 1922-27
Associate Professor of Organic Chemistry 1927-38
Professor of Organic Chemistry 1938-63
Professor of Organic Chemistry, Emeritus, 1963-1969
- Correspondence, outgoing. 109 items, including typed carbons and handwritten drafts. (Box 1, Folder 1-7)
- Correspondence, incoming. 474 items, from 179 correspondents. Abernethy -- Prout. (Box 1, Folder 8-25)
- Correspondence, incoming. 474 items, from 179 correspondents. Quayle -- Zelinski, + incomplete signatues. (Box 2, Folder 1-6)
- Referee work correspondence (Journal of American Chemical Society, Journal of Organic Chemistry, etc.), outgoing and incoming. Outgoing, 59 items. Incoming, 56 items, from George H. Coleman, Marshall Gates, Arthur B. Lamb, and W. Albert Noyes, Jr. Many of the letters have Professor Ingersoll's handwritten comments on the backs. (Box 2, Folder 7-8)
- Correspondence, incoming -- postcards (requests for reprints, notices of arrival of manuscripts, etc.), 183 items. (Box 2, Folder 9-10)
- Manuscripts of articles, handwritten drafts, typed originals and carbons, etc., some including reprint. Note: the first seven are in Professor Ingersoll's order (chronological?); the rest are arranged alphabetically by title., DeWitt/Ingersoll, "Preparation of Pure N'Acetyl-R-Leucine and L-Leucine" Ingersoll/DeWitt, npreparation and Resolution of dl- - Fenchylamine" Overby/Ingersoll, "The Resolution of Amino Acids. I. Phenylaline and Valine" Huffman/Ingersoll, "The Resolution of Amino Acids. II. Isoleucine" Wheeler/Ingersoll, "The Resolution of Amino Acids. III. Methioninen DeWitt/Ingersoll, "N-Acylamino Acids, A New Class of Resolving Agents" Kearley/Ingerson, "The Resolution of Amino Acids. IV. Lysine" Prout/Cason/Ingersoll, "Branched-Chain Fatty Acids. V. The Synthesis of Optically Active 10-Methyloctadecanoic Acids" Bircher/Ingersoll/Armendt/Cook, "The Electrolytic Preparation of Semicarbazine Sulfate" Ingersoll/Robbins, "Esters of the Procaine Type Derived from Nicotinic Acid" Ingersoll/Brown/Kim/Beauchamp/Jennings, "Extensions of the Leuckart Synthesis of Amines" Ingersoll, "A Method for the Complete, Mutual Resolution of Inactive Acids and Bases" Ingersoll/Armendt, "Nitrourea," "Semicarbazine Sulfate," "Hydrocinnamic Acid" and "Hippuric Acid" Ingersoll/Babcock, "The Preparation and Optical Resolution of Ammonium" Ingersoll, "The Reduction of Organic Compounds by Electrolytic Amalgams" Huffman/Ingersoll, "The Resolution of Amino Acids" Ingersoll, "A Second New Method for the Complete Resolution of Externally Compensated.Acids and Bases" Ingersoll/White, "Solubility Relationships among Optically Isomeric Salts. I. The Malates of Alpha-Para-Venylethylamine" Ingersoll/Burns, "Solubility Relationships among Optically Isomeric Salts. II. The Camphorates of Alpha-ParaTolylethylamine" Ingersoll/Babcock/Burns, "Solubility Relationships among Optically Isomeric Salts. III. The Mandelates and Alpha-Bromocamphor-Pi-Sulfonates of Alpha-Phenylethylamine and Alpha-Para-Tolylethylamine" Ingersoll/Little, "Solubility Relationships among Optically Isomeric Salts. IV. Salts of 6,6'-Dinitrodiphenic Acid, a New Type Resolving Agent" Bircher/Ingersoll/Armendt, "Studies on the Electrolytic Reduction of Organic Compounds. I. Selection of a Reduction Reaction Suitable for a Quantitative Study of the Cathode Process" Ingersoll/Bircher/Cook, "Studies on the Electrolytic Reduction of Organic Compounds. II. The Preparation of Semicarbazine Sulfate" Ingersoll/Brown/Kim/Beauchamp/Jennings, "Studies on the Leuckart Reaction" Ingersoll(?), "The Synthesis of 10-Methyloctadecanoic Acid" Prout/Cason/Ingersoll, "The Synthesis of Tuberculostearic Acid" Dickison/Ingersoll, "The Terpenoid Amines. I. The Isomeric Thujylamines" Ingersoll(?), "3-Methylhendecanoic Acid" (Experimental) Ingersoll(?), "Experimental" (Box 2, Folder 11-19)
- Manuscripts of articles, handwritten drafts, typed originals and carbons, etc., some including reprint. Note: the first seven are in Professor Ingersoll's order (chronological?); the rest are arranged alphabetically by title., DeWitt/Ingersoll, "Preparation of Pure N'Acetyl-R-Leucine and L-Leucine" Ingersoll/DeWitt, npreparation and Resolution of dl- - Fenchylamine" Overby/Ingersoll, "The Resolution of Amino Acids. I. Phenylaline and Valine" Huffman/Ingersoll, "The Resolution of Amino Acids. II. Isoleucine" Wheeler/Ingersoll, "The Resolution of Amino Acids. III. Methioninen DeWitt/Ingersoll, "N-Acylamino Acids, A New Class of Resolving Agents" Kearley/Ingerson, "The Resolution of Amino Acids. IV. Lysine" Prout/Cason/Ingersoll, "Branched-Chain Fatty Acids. V. The Synthesis of Optically Active 10-Methyloctadecanoic Acids" Bircher/Ingersoll/Armendt/Cook, "The Electrolytic Preparation of Semicarbazine Sulfate" Ingersoll/Robbins, "Esters of the Procaine Type Derived from Nicotinic Acid" Ingersoll/Brown/Kim/Beauchamp/Jennings, "Extensions of the Leuckart Synthesis of Amines" Ingersoll, "A Method for the Complete, Mutual Resolution of Inactive Acids and Bases" Ingersoll/Armendt, "Nitrourea," "Semicarbazine Sulfate," "Hydrocinnamic Acid" and "Hippuric Acid" Ingersoll/Babcock, "The Preparation and Optical Resolution of Ammonium" Ingersoll, "The Reduction of Organic Compounds by Electrolytic Amalgams" Huffman/Ingersoll, "The Resolution of Amino Acids" Ingersoll, "A Second New Method for the Complete Resolution of Externally Compensated.Acids and Bases" Ingersoll/White, "Solubility Relationships among Optically Isomeric Salts. I. The Malates of Alpha-Para-Venylethylamine" Ingersoll/Burns, "Solubility Relationships among Optically Isomeric Salts. II. The Camphorates of Alpha-ParaTolylethylamine" Ingersoll/Babcock/Burns, "Solubility Relationships among Optically Isomeric Salts. III. The Mandelates and Alpha-Bromocamphor-Pi-Sulfonates of Alpha-Phenylethylamine and Alpha-Para-Tolylethylamine" Ingersoll/Little, "Solubility Relationships among Optically Isomeric Salts. IV. Salts of 6,6'-Dinitrodiphenic Acid, a New Type Resolving Agent" Bircher/Ingersoll/Armendt, "Studies on the Electrolytic Reduction of Organic Compounds. I. Selection of a Reduction Reaction Suitable for a Quantitative Study of the Cathode Process" Ingersoll/Bircher/Cook, "Studies on the Electrolytic Reduction of Organic Compounds. II. The Preparation of Semicarbazine Sulfate" Ingersoll/Brown/Kim/Beauchamp/Jennings, "Studies on the Leuckart Reaction" Ingersoll(?), "The Synthesis of 10-Methyloctadecanoic Acid" Prout/Cason/Ingersoll, "The Synthesis of Tuberculostearic Acid" Dickison/Ingersoll, "The Terpenoid Amines. I. The Isomeric Thujylamines" Ingersoll(?), "3-Methylhendecanoic Acid" (Experimental) Ingersoll(?), "Experimental" (Box 3, Folder 1-20)
- Ingersoll, "Laboratory Textbook of Organic Chemistry" --revision (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Experiments and lecture notes, Physics experiments, 1917-1918 Notebook of experiments Organic chemistry lecture notes, 1919 Physics experiments, University of Illinois, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 22-25)
- Experiments and lecture notes, Physics experiments, 1917-1918 Notebook of experiments Organic chemistry lecture notes, 1919 Physics experiments, University of Illinois, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 1-4)
- Lecture notes and outlines, Vanderbilt University: Chemistry 221, 421, and 523 (stereochemistry) (Box 4, Folder 5-13)
- Chemistry Department, Vanderbilt University: departmental matters, miscellaneous materials, Includes the following reports, etc., by Professor Ingersoll: "Annual Report for Organic Division, 1947-48" "Chemical Library Needs in the Nashville Area, 1935-36" "Organization of Proposed Graduate and Research Facilities in the Sciences," 1948 "A Plan for a Junior Departmental Staff" Also includes material relating to faculty publications, Sigma Xi, Chemistry Library, etc., and an anonymous typewritten poem, "The Midnite Rhyme of Mack the Queer" (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Report of the Division of Natural Sciences, Studies and Proposals for ilnprovement and Expansion, June 1940 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- American Chemical Society inspections -- reports, University of Alabama and Alabama Polytechnic Institute, 1941, etc. (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Natural Science Research Fund, Statement Concerning Policy and Administration by the Committee on Research in the Natural Sciences, June 1945 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- The Joint University Libraries, A Survey of Resources Needed and Their Estimated Cost, December 1948 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Student advisee records (this material is closed to all researchers) (Box 5, Folder 6-13)
- Student research, student papers, research and notes by other persons, etc. (Box 6, Folder 1-8)
- Laboratory notes, laboratory processes and apparatus, etc. (Box 6, Folder 9-11)
- Research notes, arranged alphabetically by topic, B-Fenchylamine Hydrochloride series Carbohydrates Carotenes Carotenoids Cedrene Literature d-Bromocamphor-Sulfonic Acid and Salts Experiments on Attempted Complete Resolution of -Phenyl- theylamine, etc. (Conover/Ingersoll) Extensions of the Leuckart Synthesis of Amines Fenchylamines Fenchylamines - Study of the So-Called d-Series, The Fenchylamine Mandelates and Reciprocal Resolution Leuckart Reaction Methods of Structural Proof Oxidizing Agents Resolution Resolution of Amino Acids Resolution of Phenylisopropylcarbinamine (Mandelates) Resolution of various acids Sesquiterpenes The Simple Natural Bases and Alkaloids Sources of Terpenoids, etc. Stereochemistry - Special Notes on Conformations Sulfonic Acids of Camphor and Its Derivatives Terpenes, Introduction - Monoterpenes Thujone and its Derivatives Dickison, Sherey (current research) Tractation of Cedrene Acids and other experiments on cedrene derivatives Work in progress (Box 6, Folder 12-14)
- Research notes, arranged alphabetically by topic, B-Fenchylamine Hydrochloride series Carbohydrates Carotenes Carotenoids Cedrene Literature d-Bromocamphor-Sulfonic Acid and Salts Experiments on Attempted Complete Resolution of -Phenyl- theylamine, etc. (Conover/Ingersoll) Extensions of the Leuckart Synthesis of Amines Fenchylamines Fenchylamines - Study of the So-Called d-Series, The Fenchylamine Mandelates and Reciprocal Resolution Leuckart Reaction Methods of Structural Proof Oxidizing Agents Resolution Resolution of Amino Acids Resolution of Phenylisopropylcarbinamine (Mandelates) Resolution of various acids Sesquiterpenes The Simple Natural Bases and Alkaloids Sources of Terpenoids, etc. Stereochemistry - Special Notes on Conformations Sulfonic Acids of Camphor and Its Derivatives Terpenes, Introduction - Monoterpenes Thujone and its Derivatives Dickison, Sherey (current research) Tractation of Cedrene Acids and other experiments on cedrene derivatives Work in progress (Box 7, Folder 1-15)
- Research notes, arranged alphabetically by topic, B-Fenchylamine Hydrochloride series Carbohydrates Carotenes Carotenoids Cedrene Literature d-Bromocamphor-Sulfonic Acid and Salts Experiments on Attempted Complete Resolution of -Phenyl- theylamine, etc. (Conover/Ingersoll) Extensions of the Leuckart Synthesis of Amines Fenchylamines Fenchylamines - Study of the So-Called d-Series, The Fenchylamine Mandelates and Reciprocal Resolution Leuckart Reaction Methods of Structural Proof Oxidizing Agents Resolution Resolution of Amino Acids Resolution of Phenylisopropylcarbinamine (Mandelates) Resolution of various acids Sesquiterpenes The Simple Natural Bases and Alkaloids Sources of Terpenoids, etc. Stereochemistry - Special Notes on Conformations Sulfonic Acids of Camphor and Its Derivatives Terpenes, Introduction - Monoterpenes Thujone and its Derivatives Dickison, Sherey (current research) Tractation of Cedrene Acids and other experiments on cedrene derivatives Work in progress (Box 8, Folder 1-12)
- Reprints - enclosed in correspondence; pertinent to leuckart reaction; on resolution, amines, amino acids, etc.; by Moore and Stein; interesting and historical; miscellaneous (Box 8, Folder 13-15)
- Reprints - enclosed in correspondence; pertinent to leuckart reaction; on resolution, amines, amino acids, etc.; by Moore and Stein; interesting and historical; miscellaneous (Box 9, Folder 1-7)
- Miscellaneous publications (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Ingersoll - student folders
  - Brown, Elbert Lindsay III
  - Brown, Willis Ellsworth, Jr. Fr. 9/56
  - Davis, William Gray Fr. 9/57
  - Davis, John Robert Fr. 9/58
  - Dillard, Samuel Henry, Jr. Fr.9/56
  - Elberfield, Harold Talley Fr.9/58
  - Friedman, Lawrence Ellis Fr. 9/57
  - Geist, Richard Elmer Fr. 9/56
  - Jackson, Ernest Oven, Jr. Fr. 9/58
  - Mayes, Ben Richardson, Jr. Transf. 9/59
  - Morrissey, Anthony Ten Eyck Fr. 9/58
  - Ovitt, Theron Wright Fr. 9/57
  - Perry, James Murray, Jr. Fr. 9/56
  - Perry, John Kil.lebrew Fr. 9/56
  - Pond, Trellou Joseph, Jr. Fr. 9/58
  - Ralph, William Bennett, Jr. Fr.9/59
  - Russ, Howard Kent Fr. 9/s59
  - Shanklin, Diana Crain Fr. 9/57
  - Shull, Ann Tillman Fr. 9/56
  - Smith, James Roy Transf. 9/58
  - Smithwick, Walter III Fr. 9/57
  - Thorpe, George Melvin Fr. 9/56
  - Threlkel, James Bentley Transf. 9/57
  - Threlkel, Robert Hays Fr. 9/58
  - Tweedy, Charles Enzor III Fr.9/57
  - Vaught, Patricia Transf. 9/57
  - Whittington, Richard Lydell Fr. 9/57
  - Wolff, John McDowell Fr. 9/58
  - Wright, Donald Arthur Fr. 9/56
  - York, Paul Sandidge Fr. 9/56
  - Yusk, John Francis Fr. 9/59
Ingersoll -- Index to Incoming Correspondence
ABERNETHY, John Leo (University of Redlands) - 2 (1961)
ADAMS, Clark - 3 (1942-44)
ADAMS, Roger (University of Illinois) - 2 (1940, 1948)
ADKINS, Homer (National Defense Research Committee, University of Wisconsin) - 2 (1942, 1948)
ALLEN, C. F. H. (Organic Syntheses, McGill University) - 2 (1932)
ALLEN, Ernest M. (Federal Security Agency) - 1 (1951)
AMERINE, Maynard A. (University of California) - 1 (1940)
ANDERSON, Rudolph J. (Yale University) - 1 (1947)
ARMISTEAD, Bill (Corning Glass Works) - 2 (1941, 1948)
ARMSTRONG, A. D. (Fritzsche Brothers, Inc.) - 4 (1932, 1934-35)
BABCOCK, Sidney H., Jr. (University of Illinois, University of California) - 13 (1931-36)
BAILAR, John C., Jr. (University of Illinois) - 2 (1942)
BAILEY, Lowell F. (Tennessee Valley Authority) - 1 (1946)
BALTZLY, Richard (Wellcome Research Laboratories) - 2 (1948)
BARNES, H. M. (General Foods Corporation) - 1 (1947)
BARTLETT, Shirley C., Jr. - 2 (1945, 1948)
BASS, Allan D. (Syracuse University) - 1 (1946)
BEHRENS, Otto K. (Lilly Research Laboratories) - 2 (1942)
BERG, J. Raymond (Jondell Products, Inc.) - 1 (1952)
BERLIN, Freie Universitat - 1 (1953)
BILLINGS, Erle M. (American Chemical Society) - 23 (1940-42)
BLATT, A. H. (Organic Syntheses) - 2 (1938)
BOLGAR, Michael (Tracerlab) - 1 (1962)
BOSEE, R. A. (Endo Products, Inc.)- 1 (1939)
BOUGHTON, W. A. (Journal of the American Chemical Society) - 1 (1925)
BOWEN, Murray - 2 (1947)
BOWMAN, Robert A., Jr. (National Defense Research Committee) - 2 (1942)
BRICE, A. T. (Headquarters Huntsville Arsenal) - 1 (1942)
BRIGHT, Robert D. - 3 (1940-41)
BROCKMAN, R. Wallace (Southern Research Institute) - 4 (1952, 1958)
BRUBAKER, M. M. (DuPont Experimental Station) - 2 (1936)
BRUNINGS, Karl J. (New York University) - 1 (1945)
BUELL, Bennett - 3 (1939, 1942, 1946)
BURNS, F. B. - 2 (1932)
BURR, John G., Jr. - (1948)
CAIN, Cornelius K. (University of Illinois) - 1 (1940)
CARPENTER, D. C. (New York State Agricultural Experiment Station) - 2 (1951-52)
CASON, James (DePauw University, National Defense Research Committee, University of California) - 32 (1934-37, 1941-42, 1945-47)
COLE, Martin (Alabama Ordnance Works) - 2 (1942)
CONANT, James B. (Harvard University) - (1929)
CONNOR, Ralph (Office of Scientific Research and Development) - 1 (1942)
CONROY, E. H. (Tennessee Corporation) - 1 (1947)
COOPER, Oscar (United States Department of Interior) - 1 (1941)
COPE, Arthur C. (Massachusetts Institute of Technology) - 6 (1945, 1948)
COPENHAVER, J. E. "Dutch" (University of South Carolina) - 2 (1937, 191)
CROOKS, H. M., Jr. (Parke, Davis & Company) - 1 (1952)
DAVIDSON, Philip - 1 (1948) (to Harvie Branscomb)
DeWITT, H. D. (Westminster College) - 1 (1956)
du VIGNEAUD, Vincent (Cornell University Medical College) - 3 (1948-49)
DUNN, M. S. (University of California) - 1 (1947)
EASTES, Frank E. - 1 (1954)
EKSTRAND, Torsten (Astra) - 1 (1952)
FARRAR, R. Lynn, Jr. - 2 (1945)
FARRELL, Joanne - 1 (1946)
FIELD, Lamar, Jr. (Massachusetts Institute of Technology) - 4 (1948)
FISHER, H. L. (U.S. Industrial Chemicals, Inc.) - 1 (1942)
FLYNN, Edwin H. (Lilly Research Laboratories) - 3 (1953-54).
FOREMAN, E. Leon (Lakeside Laboratories, Inc.) - 5 (1938, 1943, 1946)
FOYE, William O. - 1 (1948).
FRIEDMAN, Lester (Ohio State University) - 1 (1952)
GATES, Marshall (Journal of the American Chemical Society) - 2 (1951)
GIBBS, Owen S. (Plough, Inc.) - 2 (1942)
GIBSON, R. E. (National Academy of Sciences) - 1 (1960)
GILMAN, Henry (Iowa State College) - 3 (1925-26)
GLASS, Lewis S. (U.S. Department of Agriculture) - 1 (1943)
GRALOW, Ray C. (Corn Products Sales Company) - 1 (1948)
GRAHAM, Edward (Gulf Red Cedar Company) - 2 (1941)
GREENSTEIN, Jesse P. (Federal Security Agency) - 1 (1951)
GUY, J. Sam - 1 (1940)
HALEY, J. B. - 3 (1958-59)
HALL, S. A. (U.S. Department of Agriculture) - 3 (1943)
HAMILTON, C. S. (University of Nebraska) - 1 (1945)
HANSCH, Corwin - 1 (1945)
HARE, C. L. (Alabama Polytechnic Institute) - 2 (1940-41)
HEEREN, M. H. (Armour Research Foundation) - 2 (1942-43)
HEIDELBERGER, Charles (University of California) - 2 (1947)
HENSLEY, W. A. (Georgetown College) - 1 (1940)
HESSE, Prof. (Pharmacology Institute, Breslau) - 4 (1932-33)
HOLBERT, J. M. (University of Chattanooga) - 2 (1942, 1945)
HOLLINSHEAD, Henry (Mayo Clinic) - 1 (1953)
ROMBERGER, A. W. (University of Louisville) - 4 (1940, 1942)
HOOVER Truck Co., Inc. - 1 (1941)
HOWE, E. E. (Merck & Company, Inc.) - 2 (1949)
HUDDLE, H. B. (State Teachers College) - 3 (1940-41, 1946)
HUFFMAN, E. W. D. (Huffinan Microanalytical Laboratories) - 1 (1945)
HURD, Charles D. (Northwestern University) - 1 (1948)
ISBELL, A. F. - 1 (1948)
JACKSON, Kirby E. (Georgia School of Technology, University of Alabama) -3 (1934, 1938, 1946)
JACOBS, Thomas L. (University of California) - 2 (1945)
JENKINS, Russell L. (Monsanto Chemical Company) 1 (1948)
JOHNSON, John R. (Cornell University) - 2 (1945, 1950)
JONES, E. V. (Birmingham-Southern College) - 2 (1941)
JONES, Herman D. (Alabama Polytechnic Institute) - 1 (1941)
KAMM, Oliver (Parke, Davis & Company) - 1 (1928)
KAYE, Irving Allan (Brooklyn College) - 2 (1953)
KENNER, G. W. (Cambridge University) - 1 (1951)
KORNBLUM, Nathan (Purdue University) - 1 (1950)
LaFORGE, F. B. (U.S. Department of Agriculture) - 1 (1926)
LAMB, Arthur B. (Journal of the American Chemical Society)- 15 (1924, 1928, 1931-32, 1934, 1939, 1944, 1947)
LANDAUER, Walter (University of Connecticut) - 6 (1942-43)
LATIMER, J. Marion - 2 (1932, 1940)
LAUER, Walter M. (University of Minnesota) - 1 (1948)
LAZIER, Wilbur A. (Southern Research Institute) - 1 (1946)
LICHTENBERG, Albert (American Glossite Company, Inc.) - 2 (1944)
LINKSLEY, E. J. (Corn Products Sales Co.)1 (1950)
LITTLE, Julian R. - 4 (1934-35, 1937, 1948)
LITTMANN,. E. R. (Hercules Power Company) - 1 (1936)
LLOYD, Stewart J. (University of Alabama) - 3 (1941)
LUSTIG, Otto - 1 (1960)
LYCAN, W. H. (Pittsburgh Plate Glass Company) - 1 (1945)
MAGEE, John L. - 1 (1937)
MANN Fine Chemicals, Inc. - 4 (1950)
MARVEL, C. Speed (University of Illinois) - 16 (1924, 1936-37, 1940, 1942, 1945, 1948)
McELVAIN, S. M. (University of Wisconsin) - 2 (1941, 1947)
McENIRY, Mary Brown (American Cast Iron Pipe Company, Stetson University) - 5 (1940, 1942-43)
MILLER, Meredith - 1 (1945)
MONTGOMERY, John - 1 (1946)
MOORE, M. W. (Cavalier Corporation) - 1 (1941)
MOORE, Maurice L. (Sharp and Dohme, Frederick Stearns & Company) 10 (1942-44)
MOORE, Stanford (University of Wisconsin, Rockefeller Ins itute) - 3 (1935, 1938, 1958)
MOYER, W. W. (A.E. Staley Manufactu ing Company) - 1 (1942)
NEWMAN, Melvin S. (Ohio State University) - 1 (1951)
NIEMANN, Carl (California Institute of Technology) - 1 (1945)
ONCKEN, Mildred (Pacini Laboratories, Inc.) - 1 (1935)
OVERBY, Lacy (Abbott Laboratories, University of Illinois) - 3 (1949-50, 1962)
PARSONS, Charles L. (American Chemical Society) - 1 (1942)
PEARSON, Donald E. (Massachusetts Institute of Technology)- 6 (1945, 1948)
PETERSON, Merlin D. - 1 (1944)
PITTMAN, Frank - 1 (n.d.)
PLIMPTON, H. (Corn Products Refining Company) - 1 (1948)
POLLACK, Robert L. (University of Tennessee) - 1 (1952)
PROUT, Franklin (Northwestern University, De Paul University) - 18 (1945, 1947-49, 1960)
QUAYLE, Osborne R. (Emory University) - 3 (1940, 1946, 1947)
RABJOHN, Norman - 1 (1948)
READ, John (St. Andrews University) - 4 (1928-29)
RICE, Harold L. (University of Wisconsin) - 2 (1948)
RIEGEL, Byron (Northwestern University) - 2 (1948)
ROGERS, A. O. (DuPont Company) - 3 (1948)
ROGERS, M. A. T. - 1 (1944)
ROYALS, E. Earl (Georgia School of Technology) - 1 (1945)
RYER, A. I. (Schering Corporation) - 1 (1951)
SCHOBEL, A. (Chemistry Institute, Hannover) - 1- (1951)
SEYMOUR, Dexter (University of California) - 1 (1945)
SHACKLETON, John W. - 1 (1938)
SHAPIRO, Jacob W. (Columbia, Tenn., Central High School) - 1 (1945)
SHEEHAN, John C. (Massachusetts Institute of Technology) - 1 (1948)
SHONLE, H. A. (Lilly Research Laboratories) - 6 (1936, 1938, 1942)
SHRINER, Ralph (Indiana University) -- 1 (1942)
SHUMACKER, Harris B., Jr. (Johns Hopkins University) - 3 (1931, 1934)
SKELL, Philip S. (University of Portland) - 1 (1949)
SMITH, Howard E. (University of Zurich) - 1 (1959)
SNYDER, H. R. (University of Illinois) - 1 (1947)
SPICER, Walter E., Jr. - 2 (1946)
STACY, Gardner W. (Cornell University Medical College) - 5 (1948)
STANIER, Roger Y. (University of California) - 2 (1948)
SUMERFORD, W. T. (Mead Johnson & Company) - 1 (1959)
SUNDET, Sherman A. - 2 (1948)
SUTER, C. M. (Sterling-Winthrop Research Insitutte) - 12 (1949-51)
SWAIN, Robert E. (American Chemical Society) - 3 (1940)
SWANEY, Miller W. (Esso Laboratories) - 1 (1945)
TAINTER, M. L. (Sterling-Winthrop Research Institute) - 1 (1950)
TENNEY, E. P. (International Minerals & Chemical Corporation) - 4 (1951-52).
THOMAS, George R. (University of Illinois) - 3 (1948)
THOMAS, McCalip J. (A. E. Staley Manufacturing Company) -10 (1941-43, 1948)
THWAITE, Walter E., Jr. (Research Corporation) - 2 (1959-60)
TINSLEY, John S. - 1 (1931).
VERNON, C. C. (University of Louisville) - 1 (1942)
VOORHIES, Samuel, Jr. (U.S. Department of Agriculture) - 2 (1941, 1945)
VOSE, R. W. (Chicopee Manufacturing Company) - 1 (1944)
WALTCHER, Irving (State University of New York) - 3 (1944, 1948, n.d.)
WENNERBERG, Arnold - 1 (1948)
WHEELER, Glenn P. (Southern Research Institute) - 12 (1946-48, 1950-51)
WHITE, E. Gurney (University of Pittsburgh) - 3 (1930, 1932, 1934)